firework plots
influential plots
levelplot and dynamic graphics

dirs.substring(dirs.length()-(global_depth-1))

D://cs542_team_1_project/simpledb/simpledb_qing

dependent/organized

❖ Refinement for unclustered indexes:
1. Find qualifying data entries.
2. Sort rids of data records to be retrieved.
3. Fetch rids in order.
Avoid retrieving the same page multiple times.
File storing a relation R can only have 1 clustered index, but
many un-clustered indices
At most one, because we want to avoid replicating data records. Sometimes, we
may not create any clustered indexes because no query requires a clustered index
for adequate performance, and clustered indexes are more expensive to maintain
than unclustered indexes.

A clustered index offers much better range query performance, but essentially the
same equality search performance (modulo duplicates) as an unclustered index.
Further, a clustered index is typically more expensive to maintain than an unclustered
index.

An index using alternative (1) has actual data records as data entries. It
must be a primary index and has no duplicates. It is not suitable for a secondary
index because we do not want to replicate data records.

Exercise 8.3 Consider a relation stored as a randomly ordered file for which the only
index is an unclustered index on a field called sal. If you want to retrieve all records
with sal > 20, is using the index always the best alternative? Explain.
Answer 8.3 No. In this case, the index is unclustered, each qualifying data entry
could contain an rid that points to a distinct data page, leading to as many data page
I/Os as the number of data entries that match the range query. In this situation, using
index is actually worse than file scan.

Assume
we have the employees example again with 10,000 records and 10 records per page.
Also assume that there is an index on sal and query of age ¿ 20,000, such that there
are 5,000 qualifying tuples. The hash index could cost as much as 100,000 I/Os since
every page could be read for every record. It is not clear with a hash index how we
even go about searching for every possible number greater than 20,000 since decimals
could be used. An unclustered B+-tree index would have a cost of 5,004 I/Os, while
a clustered B+-tree index would have a cost of 504 I/Os. It helps to have the index
clustered whenever possible.

Selection
❖ Example :  R.attr OP value (R)
❖ Case 1: No Index, NOT sorted on R.attr
❖ Must scan the entire relation.
Most selective access path = file scan
Cost: M

❖ Example :  R.attr OP value (R)
❖ Case 2: No Index, Sorted Data on R.attr
❖ Binary search for first tuple.
Scan R for all satisfied tuples.
Cost: O(log2M)

❖ Example :  R.attr OP value (R)
❖ Case 3: B+ tree Index on R.attr
❖ Costs :
▪ cost I (finding qualifying data entries), and
▪ cost II (retrieving records)
❖ Cost I: 2-3 I/Os. (depth of B+ tree)
❖ Cost II:
▪ clustered index 1 I/O and few tuples that match
▪ unclustered index up to one I/O per qualifying tuple.

❖ Example :
▪ Assume uniform distribution of names,
▪ Then say about ~ 10% of tuples qualify
▪ Assume R is on 100 pages and has 10,000 tuples.
▪ Clustered index:
• 2 IOs + little more than 10 I/Os
▪ Unclustered index :
• 2 IOs + up to 1,000 I/Os
Selection – Hash Index
❖ Costs:
▪ Cost I (retrieve index bucket page)
▪ + Cost II (retrieving qualifying tuples from R)
Cost I is one I/O
▪ Cost II could up to one I/O per satisfying tuple.

❖ Example : Consider day<8/9/94 AND bid=5 AND sid=3.
▪ A B+ tree index on day can be used;
• then bid=5 and sid=3 must be checked for each retrieved tuple.
▪ Hash index on <bid, sid> could be used
• day<8/9/94 must then be checked on fly.

Node size should be at least:
– Root: 2 pointers
– Internal nodes: (n+1)/2
pointers
– Leaf nodes: (n+1)/2
pointers to data
primary index on secondary fields--combination

4. The use of a sorted file rather than a tree-based index.
First of all, both sorted files and tree-based indexes offer fast searches. Insertions
and deletions, though, are much faster for tree-based indexes than sorted files. On
the other hand scans and range searches with many matches are much faster for
sorted files than tree-based indexes. Therefore, if we have read-only data that is
not going to be modified often, it is better to go with a sorted file, whereas if we
have data that we intend to modify often, then we should go with a tree-based
index.
5. Choice of search key for the index. What is a composite search key, and what
considerations are made in choosing composite search keys? What are index-only
plans, and what is the influence of potential index-only evaluation plans on the
choice of search key for an index?

one key one page

【ISAM (Indexed Sequential Access Method):】
▪ Static structure
▪ No need for `next-leaf-page’ pointers. 
▪ Note that 51* appears in index levels, but not in leaf!(data entry in index)
▪ Only leaf pages modified; overflow pages needed.
▪ Overflow chains can degrade performance unless size
of data set and data distribution stay constant.
❖ Search:
▪ Start at root; use key comparisons to go to leaf.
Cost log F N ; F = # entries/index pg, N = # leaf pgs
❖ Insert:
▪ Find leaf that data entry belongs to, and put it there.
❖ Delete:
▪ Find and remove from leaf; if empty overflow page,
de-allocate. If empty primary page, leave it.
❖Cons:
- Long overflow chains may appear.
- May affect retrieve performance.
Keep 20% free in leaf page.
❖Pros :
+ Concurrent access.
Index page is not locked since it is never changed.?????

【B+ tree:】
▪ Dynamic structure
▪ Adjust gracefully under inserts and deletes.
▪ Almost always better than maintaining a sorted file.
❖ Guarantee Search/Insert/delete at log F N cost
with F = fanout, N = # leaf pages❖ Each node contains d <= m <= 2d entries. The parameter
d is called order of tree.
❖ Minimum 50% occupancy or fill-factor (except for root).▪ Typical order: 100. Typical fill-factor: 67%.
▪ average fanout = 133
❖ Typical capacities:
▪ Height 4: 1334 = 312,900,700 records
▪ Height 3: 1333 = 2,352,637 records
❖ Can often hold top levels in buffer pool:
▪ Level 1 = 1 page = 8 Kbytes
▪ Level 2 = 133 pages = 1 Mbyte
▪ Level 3 = 1332 = 17,689 pages = 133 MBytes

❖insert:
1)see if it can redistribution
2)leaf: push the middle key into a new leaf at the same level;copy up the middle key into parent node
3)middle node:if full,split into 2 nodes and push up the middle key
❖delete:
1)borrow from the sibling:push up the next key to the moving one of the sibling
2)if size<d(d<=size<=2d)after deleting, merge with the sibling and delete the parent key.
3)关注parent node(middle node) <d? no borrowing!
pull down the parent key and push up a new one from sibling

【choice of index】
Trade-off: Indexes can make queries go faster, updates
slower. Require disk space, too.

Clustering can also help equality queries if there are
many duplicates

❖ Multi-attribute search keys considered when WHERE
clause contains several conditions.
▪ Order of attributes is important for range queries.
▪ Such indexes can sometimes enable index-only strategies❖ Try to choose indexes that benefit as many queries
as possible. 
❖ Since only one index can be clustered per relation,
choose it based on important queries that would
benefit the most from clustering.

❖ If retrieve Emp records with age=30 AND sal=4000
▪ Index on <age,sal> would be better than an index on age or
an index on sal.
❖ If condition is: 20<age<30 AND 3000<sal<5000:
▪ Clustered tree index on <age,sal> or <sal,age> is best.
❖ If condition is: age=30 AND 3000<sal<5000:
▪ Clustered <age,sal> index much better than <sal,age> index!
▪ Or, <age> is good choice.
❖ Composite indexes are larger, updated more often.

【Static Hashing Cons】❖ Primary pages fixed space  static structure.
❖ Fixed # buckets is the problem:
▪ Rehashing can be done  Not good for search.
▪ In practice, instead use overflow chains.
❖ Long overflow chains degrade performance. 
【Extendible Hashing】❖ Problem: Bucket (primary page) becomes full.
❖ Solution: Re-organize file by doubling # of buckets?
▪ But Reading and writing all pages is expensive!
❖ Delete:
▪ If removal of data entry makes bucket
empty, can be merged with `split image’.
▪ If each directory element points to same
bucket as its split image, can halve
directory. 
❖ If directory fits in memory,
then equality search answered with one disk
access; else with two.
▪ 100MB file, 100 bytes/rec, 4K pages contain 1,000,000
records (as data entries) and 25,000 directory elements;
chances are high that directory will fit in memory.
▪ Directory grows in spurts.
▪ If the distribution of hash values is skewed, directory
can grow large.

【removing duplicates.】
▪ SQL systems don’t remove duplicates unless keyword DISTINCT is
specified in query.
❖ Sorting Approach:
▪ Sort on <sid, bid> and remove duplicates.
(Can optimize this by dropping unwanted information while sorting.)
❖ Hashing Approach:
▪ Hash on <sid, bid> to create partitions.
Load partitions into memory one at a time, build in-memory hash
structure, and eliminate duplicates.
❖ Indexing Approach :
▪ If there is an index with both R.sid and R.bid in the search key, may be
cheaper than sorting data entries
